[ominous music playing]
[static buzzing]
[beeping, crackling]
[electronic crackling, beeping]
[opera music playing]
[woman yelling] I am sick of this, Gabe.
I do fucking everything for you.
I am your goddamn mother.
-Oh really, Mom? Mom of the year.
-[lighter clicks]
You're fucking lucky
I didn't call the fucking police on you.
she didn't call the police on you.
Do you wanna be on my side?
I will always be on your side, Gabe.
I'm always on your side.
You're doing a fucking great job…
I look like a fucking idiot.
You screaming at me.
-All my friends are watching.
-Did you see her face?
Did you see the way she looked at me?
And your father did nothing.
[Gabe] Ha! He's too busy
living in the '80s.
He's… He's playing with his toys.
His weird, creepy shit.
-[man] Oh, give me a break.
-[electronic whining]
[electronic whining continues]
[beeping]
[chair creaking]
[computer typing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[cursor beeping]
[suspenseful music continues]
[beeping]
[keyboard clacking]
[bottle thuds on table, opens]
[suspenseful music continues]
[music intensifies]
[ominous music plays]
-[suspenseful music playing]
-[computer typing]
[cursor beeping]
[beeping continues]
[keyboard clacking]
[power turns off]
[chuckles]
[chuckles] Cool.
-[laughs]
-[record player turns on]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gabe, distorted]
Retro… Retro… Retro weirdos.
[Gabe's mom] Hiding in the '80s.
[Gabe] Who the…
Who the fuck is Barry Newman anyway?
[Gabe's mom] It's Gary Numan. It's Gary…
It's… It's Gary Numan.
[Gabe] He fucks his vinyl
more than you… you… you…
-"His tongue? Her ears?"
-[Gabe] Those old movies… suck.
[Gabe continues indistinctly]
What?
"His tongue? Her ears?"
[Gabe] He's just a fucking loser.
He's just a fucking loser.
-[keyboard key clacking]
-[distorted] Loser… Loser… Loser…
-[high-pitched screech]
-[screams]
-[groaning]
-[screeching continues]
[ominous music playing]
[keyboard clacking]
[crickets chirping]
Guys?
-[foreboding music playing]
-Laura?
Honey?
[foreboding music continues]
[gasps] I don't know what happened.
[whimpers]
[sinister music playing]
[Laura mumbling]
[beeping]
[sinister music intensifies]
[ominous music playing]
[ominous music intensifies]
[cursor beeping]
[static crackling]
[ominous music continues]
[electronic beeping]
[electronic whine]
[whirring]
[metal grating]
It's short.
I got less out of you than the others.
You're lazy.
I'm pregnant.
So you're stupid and lazy.
Don't speak to her like that.
Maybe I don't need you tonight.
Come on.
You think you're special.
You're not fucking special.
["West" by Ivy Soul playing]
♪ Yo, first crush was the preacher's son ♪
♪ First punch was Chelsea ♪
♪ That's my round
Got her back till kingdom come ♪
♪ At BAC we was the freshest, smartest ♪
♪ Since kindergarten
Pardon my pompous ♪
♪ But my circumstances
Should've had me dearly departed ♪
♪ We were starved for opportunity
And begging for immunity ♪
♪ From violence we never started
From trauma that we ain't seek ♪
♪ Moving units with cardiac
Varsity how we run it back ♪
♪ That black and teal and purple
Color my blood and my speech ♪
♪ I do this for myself
For my family and the four ♪
♪ For the West who knows me best
Since I sleeping on the floor ♪
♪ See, I've been watching family die
Since the tender age of eight ♪
♪ So I've been scraping funds together
We been tryna make a way ♪
-[keyboard clacking]
-[man mumbling]
Come on, baby.
Oh, just look at you.
I am so fucking smart.
[humming]
[scatting]
God, you're so beautiful.
[chuckles softly]
[scatting]
-[woman growls, laughs]
-[yelps]
Hey. Hey!
How is the character design coming?
-Uh, great.
-Want me to check your code?
Mmm, no. No. I am…
-[man] Okay.
-[woman] You got the nose wrong.
It is not… It's not supposed to be…
It's just an idea.
[train horn sounding in distance]
-[synth music playing on headphones]
-[man sighs]
Oh, what is that?
-What do you mean? What, Fad Gadget?
-Come on.
Synth pioneer from the greatest decade
in pop-culture history?
You shouldn't listen to stuff like that.
It's bad for you.
It's not ba…
You loved the last thing I played for you.
Run-DMC.
You think you turned me on to Run-DMC?
[laughs]
[inhales sharply]
[exhales]
How's that job hunt going?
I'm on 27 "fuck yous" and counting, so…
That's why you don't drop out.
You gotta go back and graduate.
[keyboard clacking]
Well, hey, look, once my game's picked up,
you can come program for me, full-time.
At the House of Isaac?
-The House of Isaac?
-Yeah.
[Isaac] That's actually pretty good.
[scatting]
Nice.
[woman] Just some, like,
solders need fixing.
Nice.
This thing is
a retro collector's wet dream.
-Is 70 okay?
-They're only selling them for 90.
But I am paying for the art.
[drawer opens]
[tugging on drawer]
[woman] New stock?
[Isaac] Yeah. I mean, it's just
a load of junk really, but… [grunts]
Sorry. Oh…
God, it's, uh… Sorry about the mess.
[woman] I've seen it a lot worse.
[clears throat] My mom won't eat here.
She says it's not sanitary.
I mean, I don't really like eating here,
with the bugs and the overwhelming sense
of existential…
Hey, you eaten? There's this karaoke place
that does breakfast.
They make you sing
before they bring out the menu.
We could do our duet--
Hey, I can try and clean this up for you.
Yeah, sure, uh, take it.
[Isaac exhales, clears throat]
-Um…
-What's this?
[suspenseful music playing]
Uh, I don't… know?
Looks like a bootleg.
[woman] With a 125 grand prize?
[Isaac chuckling] Curs>r.
That's actually quite a good name.
Not as good as Ghoster, but…
Think the prize is still good?
I don't know. I mean, there are a ton
of unclaimed prizes from retro games.
Couple of months ago,
I read about this guy.
He was the first person in 34 years
to complete Thou Art Dead.
He found a treasure chest in a dungeon
with a bank account number. [grunts]
[line ringing]
[on voicemail] Greetings,
this is Robert Englund,
horror royalty and Hollywood nightmare.
No fucking way.
[Robert] Or should that be
the other way around?
What?
[Robert] If you're listening to this,
then you're either a loser
who isn't paying
Mommy and Daddy's phone bill,
or you have survived Curs>r.
-That is so cool!
-[chuckles]
-What is--
-[Robert] So, congratulations.
You are worthy.
-Oh my God.
-What? Who is that?
Enter your four-digit prize code
after the tone.
-[mockingly] "Who's that?" Fuck yeah.
-[Robert] And remember, reality is cursed.
That is so cool!
[Robert] Spend that money wisely, kiddos.
-Robert Englund?
-[phone beeps]
Who the fuck is that?
Oh, come on.
[imitating Robert] Oh, you…
Your pop-culture ignorance
is becoming unacceptable, bitch.
You know that. You know that.
I just-- I didn't just call you a bitch.
Oh God.
Could be easy money.
Yeah. Yeah. Wait, no.
Technically, that is mine.
-You know Wilkies on 37th?
-Yes, I do.
Meet me there tonight at…
1:30.
-It's a date.
-It's a deal.
-[door opens, closes]
-[imitating Robert] Just help yourself.
[disturbing music playing]
[indistinct chatter on radio]
[sirens wailing]
[people talking indistinctly]
[woman] I work! I work! I vacuum. I…
I'm home.
[woman speaking indistinctly on recording]
…record our voices, okay?
-Ready?
-[kid] I wanna go swimming.
[woman] We're gonna
go swimming in a minute.
-Ricky--
-[Ricky] Will you look this time?
[woman] What are you talking about?
I always look.
[Ricky] You didn't look
when I did my big jump last week.
[woman] Right, let's do it again.
Three, two, one.
[Ricky] Love you, Mommy.
[woman] You see here,
we have to talk in the ear
and then it will record our voices, okay?
-Ready?
-[Ricky] I wanna go swimming.
[woman] We're gonna
go swimming in a minute.
-Ricky--
-[Ricky] Will you look this time?
[woman] What are you talking about?
I always look.
[Ricky] You didn't look
when I did my big jump last week.
[woman] Right, let's do it again.
Three, two, one.
[Ricky] Love you, Mommy.
[somber music playing]
Mom.
Don't let Lance in here again.
He's not helping you.
The walls.
Huh?
The rats…
they're in the walls now.
They're hungry.
I'll, uh, set another trap later.
I was thinking
we could go for a walk tomorrow.
To the park maybe?
[woman] You see here,
we have to talk in the ear
and then it will record our voices, okay?
-Ready?
-[Ricky] I wanna go swimming.
[woman] We're gonna--
♪ Fee-fi-fo, cigarillo, cigarillo ♪
♪ I'm shaking up with the trees
How I keep the leaf in the middle ♪
♪ I'm more than these hotel rentals
And dental bills adding up ♪
♪ I'm the Kennedys out for lunch
With a preacher, martyr the king ♪
♪ I'm Cardi's engagement ring
I'm America showing off ♪
♪ I'm Viacom, Viacom
I'm Chappelle in Pelle Pelle ♪
♪ And rapping like Dylan
Spell it like Dylan ♪
♪ Gave my body to Adam
He told me to lie for him ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm America at its best ♪
♪ Boom boom, nah-nah-nah-nah-nah ♪
♪ Yippee-ki, yippee-ki-yay
With the Noname ♪
♪ Started getting money
From writing the haiku ♪
♪ Yippee-ki, yippee-ki-yay
With the Noname ♪
♪ Everybody on me
I'm lookin' just like you ♪
[ominous music playing]
-[woman] Hey, Carmella?
-[Carmella] Hmm?
Ever wonder why
they have us doing this shit?
'Cause they think it's all we're good for.
I mean, this place is fucking empty.
They got us cleaning the floors
night after night.
Oh yeah, I've given it a lot of thought
over the past few months.
Pushed it around in my mind, you know?
Really considered it.
Last week, I finally settled
on what you might call a firm conclusion.
Long as they keep paying me,
I don't give a fuck.
[chuckles]
[Carmella chuckles]
[sinister music playing]
[ominous music plays]
[electronic buzzing]
[electronic whine]
-[keyboard clacking]
-[phone vibrates]
[video game music playing]
[electronic buzz continues]
You gonna order something else?
[static buzzing]
Sorry, I'd let you sit there all night,
but my asshole boss wakes up, then…
[chuckles softly]
Give me a minute.
Yeah, sure.
Uh, menu's right there.
[laptop beeping]
[suspenseful music playing]
[typing]
[cursor beeping]
[continues beeping]
Coffee.
[waitress] Say "when."
-Did you--
-Not saying "when."
-I'm just gonna keep pouring.
-When. When.
[laughs] I'm only messing with you.
Sorry.
Are you-- Are you all right?
[chuckles] I'm okay.
You do not look okay.
[computer typing]
Hey, how'd you do that?
Do what?
To my screen. The words came up
right when you said them.
I think that maybe
we both need some sleep.
[cursor beeping]
[high-pitched whine]
-[Ricky] You have to choose, Kayla.
-[gasps]
Choose or die.
[whining intensifies]
[gasps, pants]
[breathing shakily]
[cursor beeping]
I gotta take a fucking break. Yes.
[glass shatters]
[electronic thumping]
[thumping intensifies]
[gasps]
Clean up.
[glass crunches]
[suspenseful music playing]
[music intensifies]
[grunting softly]
[whimpers]
[whimpering]
[glass crunches]
[squishing]
[waitress whimpering]
[gagging]
Stop!
Please.
I… I can't.
[sobbing]
I can't…
[glass crunching]
It hurts. It hurts.
Stop!
[waitress] I can't stop.
-Help her. We have to help--
-[electronic shrieking]
[grunting]
-[Kayla] Please. Please stop.
-[grunting]
[continues grunting]
[Kayla grunts]
-Fuck. Help!
-[beeping]
[waitress] I can't…
-[Kayla] Fuck.
-[beeping]
[gasps]
[sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[indistinct chatter]
-[Mom] What's that supposed to mean?
-[officer] It's just a question.
-[Mom] She's my daughter.
-[officer] Of course.
[Mom] She works very hard.
[officer] I didn't mean
to suggest anything.
My colleague spoke to Kayla
at the scene of the suicide last night.
This is a real tragedy.
My family's seen its fair share.
There used to be three of us.
It's… It's okay.
This your little boy in the picture here?
That's him.
Losing a kid is the toughest.
Got my own two boys,
and I can't imagine ever--
[Mom] Can I get you a drink or something?
[officer] No, I'm good.
[door creaking]
Once Kayla's rested, I'd like to follow up
on her statement if that's okay.
[somber music playing]
This used to be a good neighborhood.
We were happy.
We were.
You okay there, bump?
You haven't called me that in years.
-Mom, something happened--
-Is it still there?
The pool.
They tore it down, remember?
-They don't work.
-They're all we can afford.
Lance can help.
You keep taking his shit,
you're gonna die. Is that what you want?
Is that what you want?
[ominous music playing]
This used to be a good neighborhood.
[Kayla] You see here,
we have to talk in the ear
and then it will record our voices, okay?
-Ready?
-[Ricky] I wanna go swimming.
There's my girl.
Saw you had a visit.
-[door closes]
-Fuck you, Lance.
Can't have you talking about me.
Pick up some coffee, would you?
Your mom's out.
Stay the fuck away from her.
Hey, it's my responsibility
to look out for the residents.
There's no cure for what your mama's got.
-I got the medicine--
-Keep that shit out of my house.
-I know you guys been through a lot.
-You don't know anything about us.
"Dear, Miss Edwards,
thank you for your application
for the position of junior programmer."
[Kayla] That's mine. [grunts]
"Now, unfortunately,
we regret to inform you…" Ooh.
When you gonna learn? Nobody around here
ever amounts to nothin'.
[paper rustling]
Saw the eviction notice too.
You need money, you come to me.
Anything to help…
Miss Edwards.
[knocking on door]
[disturbing music playing]
[static crackling]
[disturbing music continues]
[Kayla] I don't know how many more times
I can explain to you what happened.
Yeah, I know. I know. It's just…
I don't see how a video game
can kill someone.
I mean Pac-Man
doesn't go around eating people.
So what? I know what I saw.
Yeah, no, I know, and she sounds crazy.
She's not fucking crazy. She was fine.
Everything was fine,
then the game took control.
-Is that what you told the cops?
-It's what I'm telling you.
You don't believe me?
Kayla… Hey… Hey, I wanna believe you.
-Just tell me where it came from.
-[Isaac] I don't know.
I have no way of knowing.
It's house clearance.
-Just in a lot--
-What fucking use are you?
Wait.
Let me do some research.
-I'll get to the bottom of this.
-Yeah, you do that.
You're so fucking smart.
[door opens, closes]
Fuck.
[ominous music plays]
[phone vibrating]
[Mom panting on phone]
Kayla. Kayla! Kayla!
Mom, what's wrong?
Why aren't you sleeping?
[Mom panting] I can… I can hear them.
The rats. They're getting out.
I'll set another trap later.
-[Mom] No, no, no.
-[rats squeaking]
[gasps] They're here! They're here!
What are you talking about?
-[rats squeaking]
-[Mom panting]
-Kayla--
-[electronic shriek]
-Shoo!
-[high-pitched whine]
[ominous music playing]
[static buzzing, beeping]
[beeping stops]
[video game music plays]
[narrator] Level two.
You are in a tower.
[static crackling]
[Mom sobbing]
Please, Kay--
Kayla, you have to help me.
[sobbing] I can't do this on my own.
I don't know what to do, Kayla.
I don't know what to do.
[rat squeaking]
You gotta get out of there.
[Mom] I can't get out. I can hear it.
[narrator] Choose.
The living room or the bathroom?
Mom, you're… you're in the bedroom?
[Mom] Yeah, I'm in the bedroom.
[narrator] Choose or die.
-Get to the living room.
-[Mom] I can't. It's gonna see me.
Go quick. Hide behind the couch.
[Mom] I can't. I can't move.
-I cannot move from here!
-Trust me.
[Mom] Kayla, help me!
I'm gonna go and hide.
-I'm gonna go and hide!
-No! No!
[Mom] It's destroying everything.
I can hear it.
[narrator] There's no meat
in the living room. You're hungry.
It's trying to make me hurt you.
Bathroom or bedroom?
[Mom] Kayla. [panting]
[narrator] Choose or die.
[Mom panting]
Wait there till I tell you to run.
[Mom] What? What? What?
Run where? Run where?
Bathroom. It's in the bathroom.
I want you to go right past.
-Go straight for the front door.
-[Mom] No.
[Kayla] I need you to go right now.
-Mom, do you see it? Go! Now!
-[Mom] No, I cannot. I can't.
Okay! Okay!
[narrator] There's no meat
in the bathroom.
-[sobbing, screaming]
-[rat shrieking]
-[narrator] Meat.
-No, no, no!
-[rat shrieking]
-[Mom screaming]
[Kayla] Shut the fucking door!
[narrator] The bedroom door is locked.
Kayla, I don't know what to do!
I don't know what to do!
-Help me!
-[narrator] Charge it? Chew it?
[Mom] I can't do it, Kayla!
I can't do this!
[sobbing]
-[narrator] Choose or die.
-[Mom] I don't wanna die. [sobbing]
Kayla, I love…
I love you, and I am so sorry. [sobbing]
Go to the window.
[Mom] I can't do it, Kayla!
-You have to!
-[Mom crying hysterically]
[narrator] Choose or die.
[Mom sobbing] Kayla,
I can't hold the door!
-[rat squeaking]
-Oh Jesus Christ!
-Move, Mom!
-[Mom] I can see it! I can see it!
[gasping] Help me! Somebody help me!
[narrator] The meat is so close
you can taste it.
[Mom] No, no, no!
Jump.
It's too high!
I can't! [panting]
[rat shrieking]
-Jump out the fucking window!
-[Mom screaming]
[thudding]
[sobs]
[rat squeaking]
[narrator] A worthy player.
Same time again tomorrow for more terror.
-[screaming]
-[computer beeping]
[screen shattering]
Kayla! What the fuck?
You are fired.
[machine beeping]
[lights flickering]
[intercom beeps]
[indistinct PA announcement] ...on line 1.
[phone clicking, chimes]
-[Mom] Where's Ricky?
-Mom.
Ricky.
He wants to go swimming.
Why did you say that? Did you see him?
[ominous music playing]
[dogs barking in distance]
[Mom] I can… I can hear them.
The rats. They're getting out.
[narrator] You are in a tower.
[ominous music continues]
-[Mom gasps] They're here! They're here!
-[rat shrieking]
[rat squeaking]
[sobbing] Kayla, I don't know what to do!
I don't know what to do!
You have to help me!
[narrator] Choose or die.
[Mom sobbing] Kayla, I don't wanna die.
-[rat squeaking]
-[electricity crackling]
[narrator] There's no meat
in the living room.
You're hungry.
[rat squeaking]
[Mom sobbing]
Kayla, I can't hold the door!
Oh Jesus Christ!
[ominous music intensifies]
Somebody help me!
[music peaks]
[music stops]
[electricity crackling]
[sighs]
-[narrator] Meat.
-[shrieking]
-[gasps]
-[Lance laughs]
You trashed the place, huh?
Landlord's gonna love this.
-Get out.
-[Lance] I gotta report it.
-Unless…
-Fuck you.
[Lance] Maybe.
What are you worth?
Ten dollars? Fifteen for the hour?
You take one more step,
you'll find out what I'm worth.
[chuckles]
Everyone in the neighborhood
used to look to your mom and be like…
Well…
she was really somethin'.
Anyone was gonna make it out,
it was gonna be her.
[chuckles]
I got a 20.
[can hisses open]
[grunts]
[panting]
[disturbing music playing]
-[thunder rumbling]
-[rain pattering]
[banging on door]
[Isaac] I am coming.
Kayla?
-What the fuck?
-You have to believe me.
I… I believe you.
I believe you. Come inside.
This is some fucked up shit.
Be sure before you get involved.
I'm sure.
I'm sure, okay?
Just get in. You're soaked.
[Kayla panting]
[Isaac] You weren't kidding.
This is some fucked up shit.
Can we turn it on?
I tried.
But listen, I checked what time
it started itself up last night. 2:00 a.m.
Same time as when I first opened it
the night before.
I think we gotta wait till then.
[Kayla exhales]
Look, I'm sorry about yesterday.
Okay? After you left,
I tried to find out what I could.
It was a dead end.
And there's nothing online.
Literally. Not even an honorary mention
on the forums.
The prize line number's delisted.
I wanted to see if somehow
it was much more contemporary technology,
but there's nothing in the code
that'd begin to explain…
[Isaac] I mean, yeah,
it's just ordinary wrapper code.
[Kayla] Yeah,
so what's inside the wrapper?
Well, some old games have code hidden
in the analog loading sound itself.
-Sound is data.
-We could try to separate out the sound?
Yes, we should.
Yes, we should, Kayla.
Okay.
Where are you?
When it loads, we'll be ready.
[static crackling]
You know what I mean? I feel like
we're just scratching the surface
of interaction in, like, player choices.
Even just cheat codes.
They're cool, but they're a bit standard.
You know? You get left, right, A, B.
You get to skip a level, or you power up.
It's cool, but it's just easy.
I am gonna reinvent the whole idea.
So in my game,
if you wanna cheat, it's gonna cost you.
Like, uh… Like it's gonna hurt.
Am I boring you?
No.
I am. I am boring you.
No, really. It's…
It's good that you're making
something new.
Something that's yours.
Those, um… [clears throat]
Those designs you saw?
Those are just sketches by the way.
Those… They don't mean anything.
I like that you made me look
like a superhero.
[chuckles] Well, gotta make sure
you use your powers wisely.
You're such a dick.
Whoa! Hey, what the fuck was that for?
Do not start a food fight with me.
I am a grand master.
Go. Kayla.
-[Kayla] Ew.
-Sto-- Did I get it in your mouth? Ah!
["It's Like That" by Run-DMC
playing on stereo]
-Hey, hey! This is our song.
-[turns up volume]
We don't have a song.
What do you mean?
We listened to this, like, four times.
-That doesn't make it our song.
-[scoffs]
God, do you like anything about me?
♪ And that's the way it is ♪
[high-pitched whine]
It's time.
Oh shit. It's time?
-Wait.
-[static crackling]
-[Kayla] Isaac, hurry up.
-[Isaac] Okay. Oh, there's something.
Uh… Let me…
-Wait. Hold on.
-[violent buzzing]
-[electronic growls]
-That is fucking evil.
Oh.
I don't know what that is. What is that?
It's not like anything I've ever seen.
And, like, it's got this weird gap.
If it's coding language,
there should be a cursor.
-Some kind of command prompt?
-There should, but there's nothing.
-Fuck!
-There's nothing-- [gasps]
"Level 3."
"You are with a loyal squire."
A squire? [scoffs]
Have you been talking to this thing?
"Prove yourself worthy of the prize.
Isaac looks…"
[suspenseful music playing]
[computer typing]
[chuckles nervously, mumbling]
How is it doing that?
Ah. [laughs]
Wha-- [laughs]
It's… It's almost putting the words
on the screen before I say…
them.
-Okay.
-[computer typing]
Uh…
Well, maybe these symbols
help it interact with reality.
Bad idea.
-[Isaac] "Help? No help?"
-[Kayla] Isaac, be careful.
-It's gonna try hurting you.
-My help?
-[Kayla] We shouldn't play.
-Choose or die?
-Bad idea.
-Gotta choose.
-No, we shouldn't. No, stop. Stop!
-[electronic shriek]
-[screaming]
-Hey! Oh God!
-[electronic shrieking]
-What do I do?
[screaming] Make it stop!
[grunts, gasps]
[both breathing heavily]
What the fuck was that?
[Kayla sniffling]
[Isaac] You okay?
[thunder rumbling]
Get up. All right.
[computer typing]
[beeping]
[exhales sharply]
Oh fuck.
[ominous music playing]
That is some fucked up shit.
[tense music playing]
I mean, how… How is that even possible?
[phone beeps]
[Kayla] Blue or red?
Never pick red.
Trust me.
It's locked.
[Ricky whispering] Die.
-What the fuck?
-Well, red's not so bad.
[tense music playing]
Anything?
It's quiet.
[tense music continues]
[phone beeps]
[indistinct chatter in distance]
[Isaac] Red's not so bad.
Red's not so bad.
[tense music continues]
[ominous music playing]
[indistinct chatter in distance]
[Ricky whispering] I wanna go swimming.
Kayla. Wait. Wait.
-Kayla.
-[Ricky] I wanna go swimming now.
-[Kayla] Ricky, stop.
-Wait. Kayla.
[Kayla] Ricky!
-Ricky!
-[Ricky] Let's go.
-Let's go.
-Wait.
-[Ricky] Let's go.
-[Kayla] Stop.
-[Ricky] Let's go!
-[Kayla] Wait!
-[Isaac] Kayla. Wait.
-[Ricky] Let's go!
-[Isaac exclaims]
-[ominous music plays]
[electronic crackling]
[Isaac] The fuck is this place?
It's where my brother drowned.
[Ricky] I wanna go swimming.
-Ricky.
-No. Kayla, Kayla, remember.
It's not real. It knows you.
Don't… Don't let it play you.
[Kayla] Stop! Ricky!
[exhales]
-Shit.
-[Kayla] Ricky!
-[grunts]
-[Isaac] Kayla!
Kayla, Kayla, Kayla. Can you hear me?
Fuck! Fuck!
Come on.
[exhales] Okay, I'm coming in.
I'm coming in.
[exhales sharply]
[Kayla] Ricky?
[Ricky whispering]
Will you look this time?
[Kayla] Where are you?
[Isaac] Fuck.
[panting] I can't see shit.
Kayla?
[rustling]
Kayla!
Fuck.
Kayla, say something!
Kayla!
[Kayla] Ricky?
[Ricky whispering] Will you look?
Ricky?
-[Isaac whimpers]
-[Ricky whispering] Isaac.
-[Isaac] Is that you?
-[Ricky whispering] Look at me, Kayla.
Ricky?
[Ricky laughing]
[Isaac] Oh fuck!
[Kayla] What are you talking about?
You have to talk in the ear, and then
it will record our voices, okay? Ready?
-[Ricky] You're not… looking.
-You're gonna go swimming in a minute.
[Ricky] Will you look this time?
-[loudly] Look!
-[gasps]
[panting]
Kayla.
[eerie music playing]
[Isaac screaming]
Help! Help!
[music intensifies]
[screaming]
-Isaac?
-[Isaac grunting]
[thumping]
[eerie voices whispering]
Isaac?
[music stops]
Isaac.
[breathing heavily]
-[cursor beeping]
-No.
[static crackling]
[muffled] No.
[cursor continues beeping]
[static crackling]
[Kayla sobbing]
[grunting]
-Please-- [gasps]
-[screaming]
[both grunting]
[Ricky] Fuck.
[Kayla sobbing]
[Kayla grunting]
[both grunting]
[muffled scream]
-[grunting]
-[Ricky grunting]
[Ricky whimpering]
[Kayla gasping]
[sobbing]
[ominous music plays]
[grunts, gasps]
[panting]
[disturbing music playing]
[beeping]
[exhales]
["Nothing's Gonna Hurt You Baby"
by Cigarettes After Sex playing]
Hey.
♪ Whispered something in your ear ♪
You all right?
♪ It was a perverted thing to say ♪
That wasn't your brother back there,
you know that.
♪ But I said it anyway ♪
That's why I chose you.
♪ Made you smile and look away ♪
He loved the water.
Mom was always working,
so I used to take him swimming.
Well, I say swimming, but he just liked
to splash and play and jump around.
And the one time I looked away…
I don't know why.
It was just for a few seconds.
And when I looked back, he was…
That was it. He was lying face down.
That doesn't make it your fault.
Nobody's ever said it was,
but… that doesn't change how I feel.
♪ Nothing's gonna take you from my side ♪
And this thing…
it knew that.
It made me do it with my own hands.
It wanted to make me suffer.
[sighs]
Someday you gotta forgive yourself.
♪ Always ends in a hazy… ♪
How much do you know about zines?
The whole '80s cult thing.
And no, I promise it's not
one of my obscure retro fetishes. Look.
So kids used to play these games
with a dial-up.
Spend a dollar for the first minute,
45 cents for every minute after.
And you choose one or two,
and they could play for hours,
until their parents got, like,
a $500 phone bill.
Then they had to get creative.
And back then, everything was analog,
like, phone routing, sound…
And once they figured out
what the tones meant,
they could hack into the phone lines,
play for free.
And once you're in the phone lines,
then you'd find out anything.
So…
we could try the same hack?
Track the prize line number
using the dial tones?
-[dial-tones beeping and whining]
-[Isaac] I'm already there.
[beeps]
Upstate. [sighs]
We got ten hours till the next level.
Better get going.
[train horn sounding]
You're doing this 'cause you wanna help me
or you wanna get with me?
Both.
Oh, one more thing.
My car, my music.
-Oh, don't make me listen to your shit.
-[Isaac] No, you love my shit.
[video game music playing]
[Kayla] Isaac, come on.
Watch where you're going.
-Who taught you to drive?
-[Isaac] I taught myself… mostly.
-[Kayla] Watch out. Watch out.
-[tires screeching]
[Kayla] Slow the fuck down.
[synth-pop music playing]
[tires screeching]
-How long till the next level starts?
-[Kayla] About six hours.
[synth-pop music continues]
[brakes screeching]
[music stops]
[disturbing music playing]
Guess we're going in?
You all right?
[disturbing music continues]
We gotta find something to bust this open.
That works too.
[exhales]
What now?
[Kayla typing on phone]
[phone ringing]
Where is that?
[ringing continues]
It's coming from there.
[Robert on answering machine] Greetings.
This is Robert Englund,
horror royalty and Hollywood nightmare.
Or should that be the other way around?
If you're listening to this,
then you're either a loser
who isn't paying
Mommy and Daddy's phone bill,
or you have survived Curs>r.
So, congratulations.
You are worthy.
[suspenseful music playing]
Enter your four-digit prize code
after the tone.
And remember, reality is cursed.
[suspenseful music intensifies]
-Spend that money wise--
-[switches off]
[Isaac sighs]
[clanking in distance]
[clanking continues]
[Kayla sighs]
Guess we can forget that prize.
There's gotta be something.
There's gotta be.
Hey, hey.
Power cables.
They gotta go somewhere, right?
It goes in here.
[creaking]
Oh shit.
Oh.
Why leave it like this?
[suspenseful music playing]
They made the game here.
[suspenseful music continues]
[music intensifies]
[static buzzing]
Sorry.
"Curs>r Beta 1."
You promised me food, man.
And we go back,
March 12th, 1984 at 9:20 p.m.
This is the first Curs>r beta test.
Since we first discovered the curse,
we've been unable to identify its origins
or translate its exact meaning,
but we know it has unusual properties.
Its symbols seem to affect reality.
Each… Each of them… [clears throat]
Each of them means something.
Fire…
water
and… blood.
Their power
has lain dormant for centuries,
but the myth suggests
whenever they've been used
against a… a person or persons,
they, well, they suffer.
Oh fuck.
Pain, fear, trauma…
And the more the cursed suffer,
the more the curser benefits.
We've converted the original symbols
into 8-bit equivalents,
contained them within
a simple horror game experience,
Choose or Die.
-Choose--
-What the fuck does that mean?
Someo… Someone's been doing this to me?
I will start the test now.
[computer beeps]
[buzzing]
I am the curser.
As I cause suffering…
-[beeping]
-I will reap the rewards.
[mic feedback]
The test has started.
Curs>r. Yeah,
real fucking original, man. [chuckles]
[hits computer]
[sighing] Okay…
"You've been waiting for hours."
"They promised you food, but where is it?"
"Eat the computer?"
"Eat your arm?"
What is this, man?
Just choose one.
-This is bullshit.
-You… You want your money? Hmm?
Choose.
Hey, when this is over, when I get
my money, I'm gonna mess you up.
Arm.
[breathing heavily]
Hey.
Watch.
[groaning]
[man grunting]
Keep shooting. Get it all.
[ominous music playing]
-[screaming]
-[flesh squelching]
[groaning]
[man screaming]
[developer] It works. It works.
[panting]
-[man shrieking]
-[chuckles in disbelief]
[chuckling] It's incredible!
That can't be real.
[developer] Sometimes…
-Sometimes, a curse can be a gift.
-[man panting]
-[laughing hysterically]
-[man screaming]
[Isaac] This bit guy is fucking insane.
I mean, we gotta tell them.
We gotta tell the police.
-Or--
-[Kayla] See those?
The symbol's the command prompt. Isn't it?
It's the command prompt.
It's what we were missing.
[Isaac] We gotta get out.
We'll take it back to mine.
-[beeps]
-The fuck?
[high-pitched shrieking]
-[Isaac] What is that, Kayla?
-[shrieking]
What's going on?
It's too soon. Too fucking soon!
Level four. You're in 1984.
We gotta go. Kayla, we gotta go.
I'm gonna reinvent the whole idea.
In my game, if you wanna cheat…
How's he doing that?
…it's gonna cost you.
-[Isaac] It knows we cheated.
-Isaac, no.
-[electronic buzzing]
-Oh my, it's gonna hurt.
-What the fuck?
-[static crackling]
-[distorted] What's happening?
[static crackles]
Rewind or fast-forward?
Isaac?
[developer] Rewind or fast-forward?
Help, Kayla.
Choose or die.
-Choose or die.
-[Isaac groaning]
[vomiting]
[screaming]
[tape forwarding]
[Isaac screaming]
[tape jams, repeating]
Rewind or fast-forward?
[Isaac screaming]
-[Kayla grunts]
-[continues screaming]
[laughing hysterically]
Choose or die.
-Do it.
-[developer] Choose or die.
Choose--
[screaming]
Sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
[screaming]
[buzzing rapidly]
-[whimpers]
-Level four complete.
[gagging]
[coughs, gags]
You're okay.
[gasping]
What did we… What did we win?
Don't speak.
-[grunting] I--
-It's okay. It's okay.
[Isaac gasps]
I…
I totally turned you on
to... [coughs] Run-DMC.
[gasping]
[Kayla sniffles]
[tearfully] You're so fucking smart.
[Isaac coughs]
[gurgling]
[somber music playing]
You're okay.
-Isaac…
-[computer beeping]
Isaac.
[sobbing, screaming]
[developer] Now beat the boss.
[disturbing music playing]
["Nothing's Gonna Hurt You Baby" playing]
[sobbing]
♪ Nothing's gonna take you from my side ♪
[sinister music playing]
[music intensifies]
[engine stops]
[keys jingling]
[birds chirping]
[phone vibrating]
-Mom?
-[Lance on phone] Hey.
Where the fuck are you?
-Why do you have her phone?
-[Lance] She's resting.
It's been decided. When she's better,
she's coming home with me.
I'm gonna take care
of everything she needs.
Let me speak to her.
We're gonna play happy families.
[exhales]
[car door closes]
[static crackling]
[suspenseful music playing]
[music continues]
Okay, you motherfucker.
["Are 'Friends' Electric?"
by Tubeway Army playing]
♪ It's cold outside ♪
♪ And the paint's
Peeling off of my walls ♪
♪ There's a man outside ♪
♪ In a long coat, gray hat… ♪
[song continues indistinctly]
♪ Now the light fades out ♪
[man] Now the light fades out.
♪ And I'm wondering
What I'm doing in a room like this ♪
[man] And I'm wondering
what I'm doing in a room like this.
♪ There's a knock on the door ♪
[man] There's a knock on the door.
♪ And just for a second
I thought I remembered you ♪
[man] Just for a second
I thought I remembered you.
Amen.
[Gabe whimpering]
[mumbling, whimpering]
Who are you?
A player.
[Gabe shuddering]
[whimpering]
Won't you sit down?
[chair scraping on floor]
How did you find us?
It sent me here.
Why would it do that?
You tell me.
[Gabe whimpering]
You still playing?
Not exactly.
[sighs softly]
I collect things, you know.
From… from when I was your age.
You probably don't know what they are.
I mean, everything's
in the cloud for you kids.
So I, uh… I picked up the game
in a clearance site.
I thought it'd pass
a couple of minutes, but…
-But I think I woke it up.
-[Gabe whimpering]
And then…
after two levels,
it promised to leave us alone
if I made copies.
My friend is dead.
[sighs]
I, uh…
[smacks lips] I really am devastated.
Fuck you.
If it sent you here,
it can't be for anything good.
-You bastard!
-You let her go.
-[Gabe whimpering]
-It's okay… son.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
-[twisting arm]
-[groaning]
Now, everybody--
Everybody just sit down.
[Gabe whimpering]
You know what I think?
I think you might be
what it was looking for.
-[high-pitched electronic whine]
-[Laura gasps]
[chimes]
[Kayla] "Final level."
"Boss battle."
It thinks I'm the final level boss
and you're the hero?
Oh, that's… that's not fair.
Aren't guys like me
allowed to be the fucking hero anymore?
-You know, in the '80s--
-Fuck the '80s.
[shouting] Fuck the '80s?
You wanna be the hero?
Prove yourself worthy.
-[typing]
-[cursor beeps]
[disturbing music playing]
Choose or die.
[disturbing music continues]
[Kayla grunts]
-[plate shatters]
-[screams]
[man groans]
[exhales]
What the fuck?
[mysterious music playing]
[disturbing music playing]
[groaning]
[panting]
[groans]
[exhales]
[disturbing music playing]
[grunting]
[Gabe mumbling]
Don't shoot her, shoot me! [groans]
You fucking idiot! Shoot me, not her!
[Kayla grunts]
[Gabe grunting]
No. No.
Laura, no!
No! No!
[panting]
Do it.
[man screams]
Again.
[man and Laura grunting]
-Let go, you fucking bitch.
-[gun firing]
[Laura] Fuck you!
You're gonna fucking pay for this.
-[grunts]
-[Laura yelps]
[disturbing music intensifies]
[gun clicks]
Fu--
[gasps]
[grunts softly]
-[gun clicks]
-Fuck.
-[Laura] No, Gabe!
-[Gabe mumbling]
No, Gabe, no, no!
[grunts]
-[Gabe yelps]
-[Laura sobbing]
[grunting]
[groaning]
[laughs]
Yeah. Yeah.
[grunting]
I'm the fucking hero!
[whimpers]
[dramatic music playing]
[coughing]
[gurgling]
[grunting]
[beeping]
[disturbing music playing]
[music ends]
[humming softly]
You were never here.
Thank you.
It's the least I can do.
You saved my life.
Are you gonna be okay?
We'll survive.
[phone vibrating]
[beeping]
[Laura] What is that?
It's the real prize.
[epic music playing]
[developer] Since we first discovered
the curse,
we've been unable to identify its origins
or translate its exact meaning,
but we know it has unusual properties.
Its symbols seem to affect reality.
Whenever they've been used
against a person, they suffer.
-Pain.
-[Kayla] Pain.
-[developer] Fear.
-[Kayla] Fear.
[keyboard clacking]
-[developer] Trauma.
-[Kayla] Trauma.
Death.
[beeping]
[keyboard clacking]
[typing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[phone vibrating]
[chuckles]
[cursor beeping]
[keyboard clacking]
[phone vibrates]
Sure you can.
[suspenseful music continues]
[high-pitched shrieking]
The fuck?
[static crackling]
[shrieking continues]
[groaning]
[ominous music playing]
[grunting]
[ominous music intensifies]
[screaming]
[Kayla] The more
the one who's cursed suffers…
the more the one
that's proved themself worthy benefits.
Recovers from sickness.
Everything wrong in their life made right.
[indistinct chatter on radio]
[gags]
[vomiting]
[Kayla] One life sacrificed
so another can be saved.
Sometimes, the curse…
can be a gift.
I like that you made me look
like a superhero.
Well, gotta make sure
you use your powers wisely.
You're such a dick.
[solemn music playing]
[phone vibrating]
[developer on phone] You've suffered.
I've prospered.
Yet somehow you managed to beat my game.
Beck?
Tell me…
who will suffer next?
[ominous music playing]
Only people who deserve it.
[ominous music continues]
[static crackling]
[disturbing music playing]
[eerie synth music playing]
[narrator, echoing] Reality is cursed.
Remember, reality is the curse.
Remember, reality is cursed.
Reality is cursed.
You are in a dark tower.
Choose or die.
[ominous music playing]
More terror.
You have survived Curs>r.
You have survived.
You are worthy.
[ominous music continues]
[static buzzing]
[buzzing slows down]
[dial-tone buzzing]
[static crackling]
[static cuts out]